Bruce Tam

(647) 831-9892 | Toronto, ON | shuchuen@outlook.com www.linkedin.com/in/bruce-tam-sc/

SUMMARY

Results-oriented software developer with 4 years of experience in Java and SQL development. Specialized in Java Core, PL/SQL, RESTful API, and RDBMS. Recently graduated from Centennial College with a strong academic background in Python and AWS. Focused on backend and microservices development. Holds a Canadian open work permit.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Analyst Programmer Feb 2019 – Aug 2021

HKBN Limited - Telecommunication company

- Created Java-based RESTful APIs for 800k+ users with 40k daily hits using Oracle DB.
- Transformed PL/SQL and shell script middleware to RESTful APIs and microservices using Java and MuleSoft.
- Optimized the Java-based Restful APIs and microservices on Weblogic Server 12c to improve system performance.
- Conducted root cause analysis with Elasticsearch/Kibana.
- Provided user support for the sales and marketing teams.

Accomplishments

- Boosted build and deployment efficiency by 50% using Jenkins and Github webhook pipelines.
- Boosted system performance by over 20% by revamping stored procedures to Java solutions.

Analyst Programmer Apr 2018 - Feb 2019

TAL Apparel Limited - Global manufacturing company

- Built web applications handling 700k+ orders yearly with Java frameworks and Angular.
- Developed and maintained RESTful APIs and web applications with Java EE, JSF, Hibernate and Spring Boot.
- Revamped legacy systems to improve functionality and performance.
- Conducted root cause analysis and resolved issues in collaboration with the team.
- Contributed to Agile-based scrum and sprint meetings for requirement gathering and application design suggestions.
- Prepared user guides and organized release briefings for the 2nd Tier support.

Accomplishments

- Provided in-depth technical training for 2nd Tier support, resulting in a **50% reduction** in support calls.
- Led successful migration from Java 6 and JBoss AS 7 to Java 8 and JBoss Wildfly 11, improving performance by 15%

Programmer Feb 2017 - Mar 2018

TAL Apparel Limited - Global manufacturing company

- Developed and maintained RESTful APIs and web applications with Java EE, JSF, Hibernate, and Spring Boot.
- Created document templates with JasperReports.
- Participated in Agile methodology-based daily scrum meetings and weekly sprint meetings to gather requirements.
- Prepared user guides and provided release briefings for the 2nd Tier support.
- Provided user support for the applications.

Accomplishment

• Conducted meticulous testing, reducing critical issues in web applications by 20%.

EDUCATION

Postgraduate Certificate in IoT - System Architecture & Integration

Jan 2022 - Dec 2022

Centennial College, Canada

GPA: 4.375/4.5

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

Sep 2014 - Jun 2017

Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong

• GPA: 3.065/4.3 (Second Class Honors, Division I)

SKILLS

Languages

Java / SQL / PL/SQL / Shell Script / Python / JavaScript / HTML / C++ / PHP / CSS

Frameworks

- Java-based: J2EE / Hibernate / Spring Boot / JSF
- JavaScript-based: AngularJs / JQuery / Bootstrap / ReactJs / Angular

Software

- Development: Eclipse / Toad / DBeaver / JasperReports / Oracle Forms Builder / SQL Developer
- MS Office: Word / Excel / PowerPoint / Power BI

Database Management

• IBM DB2 / Oracle DB / Firebase / MySQL / MS Access

DevOps Tools

Git / CVS / Jenkins / JIRA / Maven / Docker

Application Servers

• JBoss AS 7 / Wildfly 11 / Weblogic 12c

Operating Systems

Windows / macOS / Linux

Cloud Platforms

Amazon AWS / Microsoft Azure

Integration Platform

MuleSoft Anypoint Platform

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

MuleSaft Certified Developer - Level 1 (Mule 4)

Jan 2021 - Jan 2023